故事可以治愈
Stories heal.
故事可以伤人
Stories hurt.
只要讲的次数够多
If we repeat them often enough,
它们就会成真
they become real.
它们塑造我们
They make us who we are.
它们有这种力量
They have such power.
这是我在
This I learned
童年最后的秋天里学到的
on the very last autumn of our childhood.
欢迎来到
宾夕法尼亚州  造纸谷
是时候把自己从坟墓里
Now it's time to dig yourselves
挖出来了  造纸谷
out of your graves, Mill Valley.
万圣节到了
It's Halloween.
但是小心  太阳下山后
But be careful, 'cause when the sun goes down,
WNXC音像店
就是女巫的季节
it's The Season of the Witch.
造纸烤肉出品
投票给尼克松
尼克松总统  阿格纽副总统
[涂鸦是骂尼克松是纳粹]
投票不如呕吐
高音部唱片
参军
我做到了  我要去越南了
I did it. I'm going to 'Nam. Yeah.
让共产党好看
Those commies are gonna pay.
美国陆军征兵站
伙计们  今晚去吓唬小屁孩吧
Let's go scare some kiddies tonight, guys.
让全世界人民
But let men everywhere
-认识到美国强大  -谢谢
- know that a strong and a confident... - Thanks.
自信而勇敢
...and a vigilant America...
今晚要和朋友们出去吗
Going out with your friends tonight?
我宁愿待在家里
I'd rather just stay in.
随时准备着
...and stand ready tonight
为伟大事业抗争
to defend an honored cause.
吸血鬼蝙蝠
[1933年电影]
弗兰肯斯坦之女
[1958年电影]
看不见的幽灵
[1941年电影]
不死之人
[1956年电影]
呼啸房间
作者  斯黛拉·尼科尔斯
斯黛拉  回话
Stella, pick up.
斯黛拉
Stella...
我不想去玩"不给糖就捣蛋"
I don't want to go trick-or-treating.
斯泰拉  斯泰拉
Stella. Stella,
我们不是为了要糖  是为了报复
this isn't about candy. It's about payback.
搜集你能找到的所有鸡蛋和卫生纸
Get all the eggs and TP you can
七点和我们碰头
and meet us at 7:00.
斯泰拉  拜托
Stella, please.
这可能是我们一起过的最后一个万圣节了
This could be our last Halloween together.
这点事你都觉得困难
If you think you have it hard,
我可是得从马桶里捞大便
I have to fish a turd out of the toilet.
你真恶心  查克
You are disgusting, Chuck.
美国加油站
小子  你知道自己要去哪吗
You know where you're going, kid?
哪有农活干就去哪
Following the harvest.
仅限今晚
Tonight only.
万圣节
活死人之夜
妈  已经好了
Mom. It's fine.
没好
No, it's not.
裆部还是有点松
Still a little loose in the crotch.
再缝一下
One more.
接我一招
Take that!
正中红心
Bullseye.
走吧  姑娘们
Let's go, girls.
给我
Hey, gimme.
吃屎吧  哈罗德
Eat shit, Harold.
汤米  慢点开
Tommy, slow down.
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
能不能有点隐私了
A little privacy, please!
我是说蜘蛛侠
I said Spider-Man.
不是蜘蛛...
Not a spider...
人
man.
人要知足
Be happy the Lord provided.
妈  行了
Mom, okay, jeez.
妈  能让我喘口气吗
Mom, can I please breathe?
-乖一点  -好
- Be nice. - Okay!
但你能不能别那样抱我了
Can you please stop hugging me like that?
你玩"不给糖就捣蛋"是不是老了一点
Aren't you a little old to be trick-or-treating?
你出门约会是不是丑了一点
Aren't you too ugly to go on a date?
你这小混蛋
You little turd.
奥吉来了  我走了
Auggie's here, gotta run.
你闭嘴
I don't wanna hear it.
我以为你会打扮成蜘蛛侠
Thought you were gonna be Spider-Man.
是啊  看多了就习惯了
Yeah, well, get used to it, okay.
东西准备好了  好戏可以开始了
I got the goods, so let's banana split.
别盯着我姐姐看  你这变态
Stop staring at my sister, you perv.
你就不能消停一下
Hey, can you not?
这些触须一点也不逼真
I mean, these antennae aren't even realistic.
再说了  蜘蛛人
And, if anything, a spider man
应该有八条腿  而不是四条
should have eight arms, not four.
行吧  最起码我没打扮成小丑
Okay. At least I'm not a clown.
最后说一次  我是男丑角
For the last time, I'm a Pierrot.
这是十七世纪即兴喜剧里面的一种角色
It's a 17th-century character from la commedia dell'arte.
小丑
Clown.
你知道那都含有什么成分吗
Do you even know what's in those?
就是那些化学毒物让我们部队得霍奇金淋巴瘤
It's the same toxic chemicals that's giving our troops Hodgkin's lymphoma
让南越南妇女乳汁结块
and curdling the breast milk of the South Vietnamese.
你还都吃掉了
And you ate them all.
所以才这么好吃的吗
Is that why they taste so good?
让开  小丑
Out of the way, clown.
书呆子
Nerd!
让开
Move!
-他不会来了  -什么  不  他会来的
- He's not gonna show. - What? No, he'll show.
米尔纳每年都这么做
Okay, Milner does it every year
今年是他最后一次了
and this year will be his last.
你在哪呢  汤米
Where are you, Tommy?
我听说校报
I heard the school newspaper
又开始征稿了
is open to submissions again.
你应该投几篇你写的故事
You should submit some of your stories.
-来偷我们的糖果啊  汤米  -不可能
- Come and steal our candy, Tommy. - No way.
我了解我们学校
I know our school.
他们会把我生吞活剥的
They would disembowel me.
庞蒂亚克卡塔里纳  是他  是他  好
Pontiac Catalina. It's him, it's him! Okay.
好  自然点
Okay, just act natural.
你说我们要去吃晚餐
You said we'd go out for dinner.
就我们两人
You and me.
吃点甜点如何
How about some dessert?
准备好  兄弟
Get ready, man.
笨蛋
Suckers!
这是什么味道
What's that smell?
是老头的内裤
It's old-man undies!
他中招了
We got him.
好  开始了  我们上  我们上
All right, here we go. Let's do this. Let's do this!
欺负这个吧  混蛋
Bully this, asshole!
混蛋们
Douchebags!
该死的  这些小混球
God damn it! Those little shits.
现在是政便时刻
And now for the poo d'etat.
吃屎吧  鸟人
Eat turd, shitbird!
该死
Holy shit.
-停车  -扑灭它
- Stop the car! - Put it out!
露丝怎么在车上
What is Ruth doing here?
小查  你这小混蛋
Chucky, you little brat!
我不知道  我以为她是出门和别的人约会
I don't know. I knew she was going on a date but not with him.
该死的
Damn it!
我要杀了他们
I'm gonna murder them!
回来
Come back!
快跑
Go!
你们给我等着
I'm going to get you!
抓住他们
Let's get 'em!
快  伙计们  快跑
Come on, guys, go!
在那边  抓住他
Over there! Get him!
九点方向有混蛋
Douchebags, nine o'clock!
中场时间  来点小吃
在树林后面
...behind those tree
要是你想检查一下的话
if you want to go check it out.
往前走  往前走
Go ahead. Go ahead.
这里有人坐吗
Is this seat taken?
我不...看来没人
I don't... guess not.
滚出我的车
Hey, get out of my car.
拜托  拜托
Please, please.
我们马上就走
Be out of here in a minute.
谢谢了
Thanks, okay.
你们干什么呢
What are you guys doing?
我们在避难
We're saving our bacon.
抱歉
Sorry.
好了  好了  没事了
Okay, okay. We're good.
-没事了  -他走了
- We're good? - He's gone.
谢了  欠你个人情
Thanks. We owe you one.
我扮的是男丑角
I am a Pierrot.
你住在车里
You live in here?
别碰我的东西
Stay out of my stuff.
知道了
Got it.
你怎么一个人在汽车电影院
So, what are you doing alone at a drive-in?
你们怎么还在我的车里
What are you still doing in my car?
我能看出
I understand you're...
你不是本地人  对吗
You're not from here, are you?
你是哪里人
Where are you from?
请原谅我的朋友
Forgive my friend.
他出生前大脑就缺氧
He did not get enough oxygen in the womb.
总比你强  小丑
More than you, clown.
你们能不能消停一下
Can you guys stop?
是他的错  不是我
It's him, not me.
我们消停了
Yeah, we're stopping.
你的朋友有点聒噪
Your friend is a little nosy.
《活死人之夜》
Night of the Living Dead.
是部好片子
It's a good flick.
你看过吗
You've seen it?
"好  文斯  照头打"
"All right, Vince, hit him in the head,
"瞄准两眼中间"
"right between the eyes."
这是最棒的片子
That's the best flick all year.
对  对  的确  的确
Yeah, yeah, it's... it is.
我是雷蒙
Ramon.
我是斯黛拉
Stella.
我是查克
Chuck.
我是奥吉
Auggie.
下车
Get out of the car.
你们似乎没听见
I don't think that you heard me.
所有人都下车
Everyone needs to get out.
马上
Now.
你也是
You too,
湿背客
wetback.
指偷渡的墨西哥人
你不会像你妈妈一样
You're not going to try and run away
想要跑掉吧  斯黛拉
like Mommy too, now are you, Stella?
你一股大便味
You smell like shit.
别碰我的车
Get the hell off my car.
前面那个  你们挡住屏幕了
Hey, down in front. You're blocking the view!
让开
Come on!
我看不到电影了
I can't see the movie!
要么回你车上  要么滚蛋
Get back in your car or get the hell out of here!
这事没完
This ain't over.
快点
Let's go.
快滚  你这白痴
Move it, you idiot.
快点
Let's go.
回你车上去  快点
Get back in your car. Let's go. Come on.
好  走吧
Okay, let's go.
我们去哪边
Where we goin'?
那边
That way.
好  我们一起去
Okay, we'll go together.
你还好吗
You okay?
失陪片刻
Just excuse me for a second.
是我说错话了吗
Did I say something?
不  是那个混蛋汤米说的话
No, that asshole, Tommy did.
她妈妈在她小时候就丢下她离开了
Her mom left when she was a kid, just like that.
人们还是不停地谈论这件事
Yeah, people wouldn't stop talking about it, though.
你也知道  我们住的这个镇子很小
You know, we live in a small town.
这些闲话说得很刻薄
Yeah, the gossip got really mean.
天呐
Jeez.
但是这件事还是会让她难受
Yeah, but it still bothers her,
我猜这种事大概永远都无法忘怀吧
so I guess that stuff sort of sticks with you.
现在我们差不多是她仅有的朋友了
Yeah, and we're like her only friends now.
要我说她绝对不和你的胃口
So, I would say she's definitely not your type.
她可是斯黛拉  肯定谁的胃口都对不上
It's Stella. She's not anyone's type.
这点我可不同意
Don't think I'd agree with that.
所有的妹子你都喜欢  这可不算
You like every girl. It doesn't count.
也不是所有都喜欢
It's not every girl.
你至少有把弹簧刀之类的吧
Tell me you at least you got a switchblade.
我能看看你的弹簧刀吗
Can I see your switchblade?
我说过我有弹簧刀吗
Did I say I had a switchblade?
不  你没说你有
No, I guess you didn't say you had...
-他有弹簧刀  -我知道
- He has a switchblade. - I know.
今天是万圣节  所以
Well, it is Halloween, so...
你想去鬼屋瞧瞧吗
Do you want to see a haunted house?
你没还真没开玩笑
You weren't kidding.
跟你说了不会失望的
Told you it wouldn't disappoint.
禁止闯入
私人住宅
违者将被起诉
我还以为在万圣节  这个地方会很受欢迎
I don't know, you'd think on Halloween, this place would be hoppin'.
以前火过一段
It was, for a while,
然后有孩子失踪了  他们就把这围起来了
then some kid went missing, so they boarded it up.
我觉得这里会拆掉建商场什么的
I think it's being torn down for a mall or something.
各位
Hey, guys.
小丑优先
Clowns first.
不是吧
Really?
行了  我们看见了
Okay, there, we saw it.
可以走了吗
Can we go now?
谁叫了胆小鬼过来
Who ordered the chicken?
不喜欢晚上待在杀害那些孩子的凶手家
Because I don't like to spend my nights in a house
我就成了胆小鬼吗
where a child murderer lived?
有人在这栋房子里被杀了吗
Someone was killed in that house?
太黑暗了
That's pretty dark.
以前谁住在这
Who lived here?
贝洛斯一家
The Bellows.
最先在这里定居的几大家族之一
One of the first families to settle here
在十九世纪末期
in the late 19th century.
建了一家造纸厂
Built the paper mill that pretty much
真是让这个镇子出了名
put this town on the map.
就不能去找找台阶吗
We could at least look for some stairs.
和我想的一样
Just as I thought.
他们把这里锁得严严实实
They got this place locked up pretty tight.
有人带笔了吗
Anyone got a pen?
来认识一下洛拉  她疯狂地爱着我
Meet Lola. She is madly in love with me.
可能是爱你的手吧
Yeah, your hand maybe.
不错
Nice.
洛拉  干什么
Lola! Hey, what?
他比你有魅力多了
He's so much dreamier than you.
贝洛斯一家有个秘密
The Bellows had a secret:
他们有个女儿  从没允许她踏出过家门一步
a daughter that they never allowed to leave the house.
传说中她有一些很严重的问题
The myth is that there was something really off about her.
真正恐怖的部分是
A really scary part
她的家人把她从每张照片上都清除掉了
is that her family erased her from every single portrait.
直到今天  也没人找到一张莎拉的照片
To this day, nobody's ever found a picture of Sarah.
他们不认她
They disowned her.
-快跑啊  小丑  -靠
- Better run, clown. - Shit!
快跑
Better run!
我打赌你抓不到我
Bet you can't catch me!
查克  如果你跳出来吓我
Chuck, if you jump out at me,
我就一拳打在你喉咙上
I'm going to punch you in the throat.
那她后来怎么了
So what happened to her?
各个地方的孩子都跑过来
Kids would come from all over
希望能瞟到怪人莎拉一眼
in hopes to get a peek at Strange Sarah.
尽管他们看不到她
And though they never saw her,
他们可以听到她的声音
they could hear her.
透过墙壁
Through the wall.
莎拉给他们讲故事
Sarah told them stories.
恐怖故事
Scary stories.
有些孩子再也没回家
Some kids never returned home.
镇里好多孩子死了
Children around town died...
他们说是中毒
Poisoned, they said.
大家都知道是莎拉干的
Everyone knew it was Sarah.
但是他们还没来得及碰到莎拉一根手指头
But before the mob could even get their hands on her,
她就把自己吊死了
she'd already hung herself
用她自己的头发
with her own hair.
根据传说
And as the legend goes,
如果你在天黑之后来贝洛斯家
if you come to the Bellows House at dark,
让莎拉给你讲个故事
and ask Sarah to tell you a story...
那将是你这辈子听到的最后一个故事
it'll be the last story you ever hear.
这是什么
What's this?
推另一边
Push the other way.
推
Push.
不是吧
No way.
就到这了
Well, that's it.
莎拉的房间
Sarah's room.
你吓不到我
You're not going to scare me.
查克
Chuck?
什么鬼
What the...
什么  那个老太太去哪了
What? Where's the old lady?
还有那条狗
And the dog?
什么老太太
What old lady?
我们得赶紧离开
We gotta get out of here.
斯黛拉  斯黛拉  我们得赶紧出去
Stella! Stella! We got to get out of here!
斯黛拉  咱们走吧
Stella, let's go!
各位  你们得来看看这个  过来
Guys, you've gotta see this! Come here.
是谁叫胆小鬼过来了
Who ordered the chicken?
闭嘴
Shut up.
她的家人就是把她关在这里的
This is where her family kept her.
把她锁起来  与世隔离
Locked her away from the world.
孤身一人  像个怪物
All alone as some sort of freak.
她肯定就是坐在这里
She must have just sat right here
透过这面墙壁给孩子们讲故事
and told her stories to the kids through this wall.
我们之前怎么没来这里看过
How have we never seen this before?
我觉得应该没人想让我们看到
I don't think anyone wanted us to?
莎·贝
我们能走了吗
Can we get out of here now?
那是什么
What's that?
莎拉·贝洛斯的书
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
这是她的恐怖故事书
It's her book of scary stories.
她还有本书
She had a book?
我听到的那个传说版本里没提到书
There's no book in the version of the myth I heard.
每个版本里都提到了这本书
The book is a part of every version of the myth.
还提到
And...
这本书是用那些孩子的血写成的
that it was written in children's blood.
那些孩子听了这些故事之后就死了  好吗
Well, kids died hearing these stories, okay?
把它放回原位
Look, let's put it back where you found it
咱们赶紧出去
and let's just get out of here now.
我去
Oh, shit!
好了好了好了
I got it, I got it, I got it.
各位  没事  快别喊了
Everybody, okay, everybody just shut up.
不  是老太太还有那条狗
Oh, no. It's the old lady and the dog!
汤米  别闹了  行吗
Tommy, stop it, okay?
让他们出来
Just let them out.
露丝  是你吗
Ruth, is that you?
-你能把门打开吗  -别闹了
- Will you open the door? - Joke's over.
如果你不打开
If you don't open it...
-我就告诉警长  -你不能这样
- I'll tell the Chief. - You can't do this! Come on!
你为什么要那样做
Why would you do that?
这一点都不好玩  汤米  快点
This isn't funny! Tommy, come on.
他是我弟弟
It's my little brother.
拜托
Please.
快他妈把门打开
Open the damn door!
-开门  -露丝
- Open it. - Ruth!
在下面  放我们出去
Down here. Let us out!
反正你也是废物
You're trash anyway.
汤米  对不起我们拿燃烧大便丢你
Tommy, I'm sorry about the burning shit, man.
希望你们能找到出路
I hope you find a way out.
没事吧
Good?
嗯
Yeah.
-快拿开  -没事了
- Get it off me! - Oh, you're fine!
不  快拿开  快拿开  快拿开
No! Get it off, get it off me! Get it off me!
-快拿开  快拿开  -没事了
- Get it off me! Get it off me! - You're fine.
-有我呢  有我呢  没事的  -有东西咬我
- I got it, I got it. It's fine. - Something's bit me!
你能来帮我一下吗
Hey, can you help me with this?
-蜘蛛跑掉了  -谢谢
- The spiders are gone. - Thank you.
天呐  奥吉  你跟条发情的公狗一样
Jesus, Auggie. Okay, you're such a horndog.
你能不能先别忙着勃起
Can you lose your stiffy for a second
帮我们离开这里
and help us get out of here?
不好笑  女士还在场呢
Not funny! There's a lady present.
女士们  在场
Ladies... present.
加油  加油  你得用力推  加油
Come on, come on! You gotta push harder. Come on.
莎拉·贝洛斯  给我讲一个故事
Sarah Bellows, tell me a story.
给我讲一个故事
Tell me a story.
莎拉·贝洛斯  给我讲一个故事
Sarah Bellows, tell me a story.
等等  等等  我听到动静了
Wait, wait, wait. I hear something.
有人在这
Someone's here.
他回来了
He came back.
-汤米  -你得...
- Tommy! - You got...
-对不起  非常对不起  -谢谢你
- We're sorry, we're real sorry. - Thank you!
我收回我说过的每一句坏话
I... I take back everything I ever said, man.
对不起
Sorry, man!
汤米  求你了
Tommy, please!
露丝  你为什么跟这种神经病约会
Ruth, why would you date a psychopath like that?
总比你这个捞大便的人强
Better than fishing for turds.
是谁开的门
So, who unlocked it?
管他呢  咱们赶紧出去吧
Who cares? Let's just get out of here.
-男丑角的扮装不错  -谢谢
- Nice Pierrot costume. - Thank you.
我就说吧
See?
这经历真"好玩"
Well, that was fun.
湿背客
该死
Shit!
抱歉出了这些事
I'm really sorry about all of this.
-他为什么这么做  -太低级了
- Why did he do this? - This is low,
就算对汤米来说
even for Tommy,
就像是在我的牛奶盒里放个屁
like "farting in my milk carton
然后让我喝掉那么低级
"and making me drink it" kind-of-low.
五年级的事儿
It was the fifth grade.
是九年级
It was ninth.
我可以试试找点东西来帮忙
I can try and scrounge up something to help.
我能行  没事  还是谢谢你
I got it. It's fine, thank you, though.
我就待在这等到天亮
I'll just stay here until the morning.
把车开去修车店
Get it into a shop.
我家地下室里有一张沙发
We have a sofa in the basement.
欢迎你来过夜
You're welcome to use it.
我真的不想惹麻烦
Look, I really don't want any trouble.
我们只需要在爸爸起床之前溜出去
We'll just have to be gone before Dad gets up.
自动调幅调频立体声台式收音机
An AM/FM stereo table radio with auto...
山姆的宠物居然是只褐鼠
Sam's pet turns out to be a sewer rat?
你还真坏
You've got some demons.
还没写完呢
It's not finished yet.
知名怪物
我小时候很喜欢看这个  你收集的吗
I used to love these as a kid. You collect them?
每一期我都看过
I've read every single issue.
从头读到尾
Cover to cover.
如果你真的想成为一个作家
You know, if you're serious about being a writer,
你不能在这写
you can't do it here.
你要搬到城市里去
You gotta move to the city.
我不能丢下我爸
I couldn't leave my dad.
那个
the,
地下室就在楼下
basement is downstairs.
地下室通常都在楼下
Yeah, that's usually where they are.
莎拉·贝洛斯的书
阁楼
猫爪
"我能提你的篮子吗"
食人怪
哈罗德
Harold.
汤米·米尔纳
Tommy Milner.
很晚了  你又喝醉了吗
It's late! Are you drunk again?
今天是万圣节
It's Halloween.
你本该把鸡蛋送去沃尔弗顿家
You were supposed to deliver eggs to the Wolvertons.
现在去吗
Now?
现在去
Now!
怎么
What?
真该死
This is bullshit.
哈罗德
汤米一直都讨厌那个稻草人
"Tommy hated that scarecrow all his life.
他拿上鸡蛋  这辈子最后一次离开
"He took the eggs and left for the last time."
汤米
Tommy...
吃屎吧  哈罗德
Eat shit, Harold.
妈
Mom!
救救我
Help me!
妈
Mom!
警察
请熄火  不要吸烟
天啊
Oh, my God.
瞧瞧这个
Will you look at this?
你不是说要去找农活干吗  陌生人
I thought you were going to be on your way, stranger?
我是想去的
I'm trying.
有个叫汤米·米尔纳的高中生
You know, no one's seen this high school kid
昨晚失踪了
named Tommy Milner since last night.
目击者说他在汽车影院和人吵起来了
Witnesses say he got into a fight at the drive-in.
你这车不会是米尔纳干的吧
Milner didn't do this to your car, did he?
我还不知道你的名字
I never got your name.
雷蒙
Ramon.
罗德里格斯
Rodriguez.
听着  我觉得你最好
Look, I think it'd be a good idea
再多待几天
if you stuck around for a few days.
明白吗[西语]
Comprende?
罗德里格斯
Rodriguez.
之前没有这篇故事
It wasn't there before.
红墨水还没干
The red ink was wet.
而且感觉确实像血  比墨水浓
And it did feel like blood. It was thicker than ink.
你怎么能吃那个
How could you eat that?
你知道里面有多少身体部位吗  七个
Do you know how many body parts are in there? Seven!
我在杂志上看到的
I read it in a magazine.
酷  他变成了稻草人吗
Cool. He turns into a scarecrow?
新奇的转折
Fresh twist.
那不是转折
That's not a twist.
我说了  这个故事...
I told you, the story, it...
就这么凭空出现了
It just appeared.
汤米甚至没去上学
Tommy didn't even show up to school.
就好像他凭空消失了
It's like he just disappeared.
大家都知道他迫不及待要去打共产党
Everyone knew he was eager to go shoot some commies.
也许他只是...提前启程了
Maybe he just, I don't know, left early?
确实有一个房间...
There was that room...
别提了
Just drop it.
不  告诉我
Nah, tell me.
在那栋房子里  我躲藏时
In the house, when I was hiding,
那个房间很旧  我是说很新  很完好
the room was old. I mean new. Perfect,
就像他们还住在那里时  我看到一个
like when they lived there, and I saw this...
一个老太太和一条狗
this old lady and this dog
他们就那么盯着我
and they were just staring at me
-那种表情...  -听听你们说的话
- with this look... - Listen to yourselves.
那栋房子里什么都没发生
Nothing happened to us in that house
除了汤米对我们做的事
except for what Tommy did to us.
如果他不见了
If he's gone,
那不是正好吗
good riddance.
我们就不该去那里
We should never have gone there,
我们就不该拿那本书
we should never have taken the book.
你们被鬼故事吓出神经质了
You let a ghost story get into your heads.
没别的
That's all it is.
我很担心
I'm worried.
汤米没去学校
Tommy wasn't at school.
他的名字出现在书里
His name was in the book.
这不可能真的有关联  对吧
I mean, there's no way it's actually connected, right?
是啊  当然没有
Yeah, of course it's not.
斯黛拉  我不能碰上警察
Stella, I can't get mixed up with the police.
我必须去看看
I have to see it.
汤米昨晚穿的就是这件衣服
It's what Tommy was wearing last night.
如果这就是汤米呢
Okay, what if this is Tommy,
而书里发生的事
and what happens in the book
就是真实情况呢
is exactly what's happened for real?
别再吓我了
Stop trying to scare me.
这就是个稻草人
It's just a scarecrow.
-你听说汤米的事了吗  -他失踪了
- Did you hear about Tommy? - He's missing.
你的书还给你
Here's your book back.
你回来晚了
You're home late.
又要去轮班了吗
Picked up another shift?
你必须去吗
You have to?
不能拒绝
Can't say no.
冰箱里有吃的
There's food in the fridge.
你一直都这么热爱工作吗
Did you always work this much?
妈妈没离开前也是这样吗
Even when Mom was here?
听说米尔纳家的儿子没回家
Heard the Milner boy didn't come home.
大家都在谈这事
Everybody's been talking about it.
接下来几天放学直接回家  知道吗
Please just come straight home next few days, okay?
好
Yep.
你给那痘痘扑够粉了吗
You got enough zit paint on there?
这是蜘蛛咬的  你个屁股痘
It's a spider bite, you butt-pimple.
蜘蛛...
A spider...
该死  我的香蕉
Damn it, my banana!
你不是要走了吗
I thought you were leaving?
希望你饿了
Hope you're hungry.
我饿死了  谢谢
I'm starving. Thanks.
我一直在想汤米消失的事
You know, I can't stop thinking about Tommy's disappearance.
肯定有什么...
There has to be some...
你从哪拿的
Where did you get that?
就在你的书架上
It was just here on your bookshelf.
不  我刚刚就在屋里  没有书
No, I... I was just here. It wasn't.
我把它放回那栋房子里了
I took this back to the house.
什么
What?
它是怎么...怎么又回来的
How is it getting... How is it back here again?
大脚趾
-怎么回事  -什么鬼
- What's happening? - What the hell!
怎么会这样
How does that work?
我们必须让它停下
But we've got to make it stop!
大脚趾
一位母亲在花园边上挖掘
"A mother was digging at the edge of the garden
这时她看到一个大脚趾
"when she saw a big toe.
"这个看着不错  胖乎乎的"
'It looks nice and plump, '
她说  "我要放进炖菜里"
"she said, 'I'll put it in the stew...'"
这算什么故事
What kind of story is that?
什么
What...
奥古斯特
奥吉
Auggie.
Auggie!
回话
Pick up!
奥吉
Auggie!
不  家里什么都没有
No, there's nothing here.
我说没有  你和杰夫周末去旅游前
I told you, I mean, the least you could have done was go to the store
至少应该去商店买点东西
before you and Jeff took off for the weekend.
不  我才不叫他"爸"
No, I'm not gonna call him "Dad."
行了  我要把炖菜吃了
Okay, I'm eating the stew.
冰箱里的炖菜
The stew in the fridge?
反正是有人做的
Yeah, well someone made it.
好  等你回来见  爱你
Okay, I'll see you when you get back. Love you.
奥吉  回话
Auggie, pick up!
我在吃饭
I'm eating.
奥吉
Auggie!
斯黛拉
Stella!
奥吉  别吃任何东西
Auggie, do not eat anything.
听着  你在下一个故事中
Listen, you're in the next story!
不管你做什么  千万别吃任何东西
Whatever you do, do not eat anything!
真好玩
Very funny.
是查克让你这么做的吗
Did Chuck put you up to this?
奥吉  这不是玩笑
Auggie, this isn't a joke.
故事正在自己出现
Okay, the story is writing itself right now.
我不知道方式或原因  但我正看这个故事
I don't know how or why, but I'm reading it right here.
一个声音吓到了他  是说话声
"A sound scared him. It was a voice.
那个声音大喊  "谁拿了我的脚趾"
"And it called out, 'Who took my toe?'"
是个尸体在找她不见的脚趾
It's a corpse looking for her missing toe.
我知道这个故事
Yeah, I know this story.
我爸过去常给我讲
My dad used to tell me this story.
我小时候特别害怕  但是...
It scared me so much as a kid, but...
有人要说那句话吗
Am I not supposed to wait for someone to say that
我什么也没听到啊
'cause I don't hear anything.
听着  我们正在看这个故事
Listen, we're reading it right here.
然后声音变大了
"And then the voice grew louder:
"谁拿了我的脚趾"
"'Who took my toe?'"
这里就我一个人
I'm all alone.
没有说话声
There's no voice.
可是肯定有说话声
Yeah, well, there has to be a voice.
只有你在说那句话
You're the only one saying it.
奥吉
Auggie!
不  奥吉  回话
No, Auggie, pick up.
奥吉  别吃任何东西
Auggie, don't eat anything.
奥吉
Auggie!
天啊
Oh, God!
奥吉  奥吉
Auggie. Auggie?
奥吉  快啊  奥吉  回话
Auggie? Come on, Auggie, pick up!
你们听到了吗
Did you hear that?
听到什么  我什么也没听到
Hear what? I don't hear anything.
炖菜里有个脚趾  见鬼的脚趾
There was a toe in the stew. A freaking toe.
书上说接下来会发生什么
What does the book say happens next?
奥古斯特非常害怕
"August got very scared.
但他想  "它不知道我在哪"
"But he thought, 'It doesn't know where I am.
"它找不到我"
"'It'll never find me...'"
书怎么会知道这个
How does the book know that?
然后他又一次听到那个声音
And then he heard the voice again...
"谁拿了我的脚趾"
谁
Who...
拿了
took...
我的
my...
脚趾
Toe.
奥吉  快出去
Auggie, just get out of the house!
他离这里只有几条街
He's only a couple of blocks away!
谁
Who...
拿了
took...
丑角派对
我的
my...
脚趾
toe?
快啊  快啊
Come on, come on.
奥吉
Auggie?
Auggie!
奥吉
-汤米  -汤米·米尔纳
- Tommy! - Tommy Milner!
让今年更加愁云惨淡的是
And as if this year hasn't been grim enough already,
发生了一起失踪案
we have a disappearance on our hands, friends.
我们的汤米·米尔纳
Our own Tommy Milner,
就在我们小造纸谷失踪了
right here, in little Mill Valley.
是我发现了这本书
I was the one that found the book.
是我带回了家
I took it home.
这不是你的错
This is not your fault.
知道吗
You know,
我生命中的每一件坏事都是我自己造成的
I caused every single bad thing that happened in my life.
我妈的离开
My mom leaving.
现在又是奥吉
And now Auggie.
不是这样的
None of that is true.
抱歉我们迟到了  露丝的痘痘粉不够用了
Sorry we're late. Ruth ran out of zit paint.
我发誓  要不是应付你压力太大
I swear, if you weren't so stressful to deal with
我也不会长痘
in the first place, I wouldn't have zits.
什么事这么紧急
What's so urgent?
奥吉呢
Where's Auggie?
奥吉不见了
Auggie's gone.
又出现一个故事
Another story was written.
就在我们眼皮底下
Right in front of our eyes.
我不明白
I don't get it.
这是什么
What is this?
这是个老掉牙的玩笑
This is a stale joke.
万圣节已经过去了
Halloween's over.
奥吉到底在哪
Where the hell is Auggie?
我们不知道
We don't know.
他父母去旅游了  他就这么消失了
His parents are traveling, and he's just gone.
你说不知道是什么意思
What do you mean you don't know?
好吧  那我们去找他
Okay, well, then let's find him!
我觉得他不会回来了
I don't think he's coming back.
-首先  -我就知道事情不对
- First... - I knew something happened.
-是汤米消失了  -我看到那个老太太...
- Tommy disappeared. - Saw that old lady...
然后现在是奥吉
And then now Auggie.
书里出现了他们的故事
They had their stories in the book,
每晚一个故事
and it happens every night.
天呐  他吃了一根脚趾
Jesus, he ate a toe?
不是你读书
You don't read the book.
而是书读你
The book reads you.
恐怕我们唤醒了什么
I'm afraid that we woke something up.
我们所有人都会有同样的遭遇
That the same thing is going to happen to all of us.
我们都去了那栋房子
We were all in that house.
不  这不是真的  好吗
No, this isn't real, okay?
故事伤不了人
Stories can't hurt you.
莎拉·贝洛斯是个传说
Sarah Bellows is a myth,
即便她是真的  她也死了
and even if she's not, she's dead.
我们得去报警
We need to go to the police.
不行
No, we can't.
他们知道汤米对雷蒙的车做了什么
They know what Tommy did to Ramon's car
他们会认为是他...
and they think that he had...
奥吉  我们得找到奥吉
Auggie! We need to find Auggie.
不能报警
Not going to the police.
我说的话他们一句也不会相信的
They'll never believe a word I say.
那我们可以说服他们
Well, then we'll make them believe.
等到他们明白过来
By the time that they make sense of everything,
我们就都已经死了
we're all going to be dead.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
如果不能报警  那我们该怎么办
If... If we can't go to the police, what do we do?
干等着我们的故事出现吗
Just sit and wait for our story to be written?
一定有阻止女巫的办法
There's gotta be some way to stop a witch.
我不相信这些
Well, I don't believe any of it.
我得走了  我的音乐剧今晚开演
I gotta go. My musical's tonight,
我再也不会被你们的
and I'm not falling for another one
白痴万圣节恶作剧唬住了
of your dumb Halloween pranks.
这不是恶作剧  露丝
It's not a prank, Ruth.
露丝  拜托  别走
Ruth, please, don't go.
我知道你想当个作家  斯黛拉
I know you want to be a writer, Stella,
-但这个恶作剧太过分了  -不
- but this prank is sick. - No!
露丝  露丝  别走
Ruthie! Ruthie, stop.
你真的觉得这样能行吗
Do you really think this is going to work?
塞勒姆的女巫审判就奏效了
It worked in Salem.
为什么  为什么烧不坏你
Why? Why won't you burn?
我恨你  我恨你  我恨你  该死的
I hate you! I hate you. I hate you. God damn it!
这就是为什么我不看书
This is... This is why I don't read books!
我们知道这本书烧不掉也毁不了
We know we can't burn or destroy it,
但我们对莎拉·贝洛斯了解多少
but how much do we actually know about Sarah Bellows?
造纸谷公报
造纸厂关闭
造纸谷镇区
人口记录
出生日期
出生地点
姓名
性别
第几胎
再生一个
艾伦
山姆
约瑟夫
黑魔法是什么
是黑魔法吗
听听这一段
Listen to this one:
在家中唯一的女儿自杀后
贝洛斯一家解雇了长期女佣
在莎拉上吊自杀后
"After Sarah hung herself,
贝洛斯一家开除了赛尔维·巴普蒂斯特
"the Bellows family fired Sylvie Baptiste
是黑魔法吗
因为他们认为
"as she and her daughter, Lou Lou,
她和她女儿  露露
"were thought to be responsible
教了莎拉黑魔法
"for teaching her black magic."
报纸上都登了  应该是真事了吧
If it's in the paper, it has to be true, right?
有莎拉的照片吗
Is there a picture of Sarah?
没有  只有她的名字
No, just her name.
莎拉·贝洛斯
不过我找到一则脑盐的广告
But, uh, I did find an ad for brain salt,
脑盐
说是能治疗头痛和便秘
cures headaches and constipation.
不知为什么没火起来
Not sure why it didn't take off.
奥吉  奥吉肯定会很喜欢
Auggie, Auggie would have loved that.
我的眼睛要看出血了
My eyes are literally gonna start bleeding,
最后一个贝洛斯也离开了
小镇命运该何去何从
但还是没有查到莎拉的信息
and we still have nothing on Sarah.
她是哪一年上吊的
What year did she hang herself?
1898年
1898.
之后短短一年间  她家所有人都离开了
In just one year, all her family members left.
不然还能怎么样
What do you expect?
谁会想留在一个跟谋杀小孩的罪名
I mean, who wants to stick around with the name
有牵扯的地方
that's synonymous with murdering kids?
不是留下
Not stick around,
我是说消失了
I mean gone.
就像人间蒸发了一样
Like, off the face of the earth.
以她父亲为例  迪欧戴特
Take the father, Deodat.
她家有一家造纸厂
The cat owned a paper mill
他走时都不把厂卖了吗
and yet he leaves it without ever selling it?
没有任何报道提到他
No stories written about him,
连封信都没有  就那么消失了
not even a letter, just disappears.
迪欧戴特
Deodat...
Deodat.
我见过这个名字
I've seen that name.
食人怪
迪欧戴特
富翁迪欧戴特想去打猎
"Deodat was a wealthy man who wanted to go hunting."
再说一个名字
Give me another name.
他们的一个儿子  伊弗列姆
One of their sons, Ephraim.
伊弗列姆
伊弗列姆·贝洛斯
Ephraim Bellows.
伊弗列姆
它们不是离开镇子那么简单
They didn't just leave the town.
他们都有自己的故事
They each have a story.
为什么
Why?
天啊
Oh, my God.
天啊  又开始了
Oh, my God, it's happening again.
她在写另一篇故事
She's writing another story.
《红斑》
"The Red Spot"?
你们看我干什么
Why are you looking at me?
怎么了
What?
靠  靠  是我吗
Oh, shit! Oh, shit, it's me?
我要死了吗
It... I'm gonna die?
我不想死  我还没破处呢
I don't want to die! I even haven't had sex yet.
一天晚上  一只蜘蛛爬上
"One night, a spider crawled across
一个年轻女孩的脸颊并咬了她一口
"a young girl's cheek and bit her."
蜘蛛  我打扮成蜘蛛侠了  我...
Spider? I was the spider man! I'm...
等下  "年轻的女孩"
Wait, "young girl"?
露丝
去了洗手间
"Went to the restroom."
不是你  是你姐姐
It's not you. It's your sister.
露丝
Ruthie?
造纸谷镇区为您献上
欢乐今宵
二十分钟后演员登台
Performers to stage in 20 minutes.
亲爱的  你得处理下那个了
Honey, you need to do something about that.
嗯
Yeah.
不是这个洗手间
It's a different bathroom.
-二楼  -好
- Second floor! - Okay.
露丝
Ruth.
让开  快让开
Move. Out of the way!
露丝
Ruth!
天啊  露丝
Oh, my God, Ruth!
救命  救命
Help me, help me!
露丝  我来了
Ruth, I got you.
没事了  没事了  我来了
It's okay. It's okay. I got you.
救命  把它们弄开
Help me, help me. Get them off!
把它们弄开
Get them off!
露丝  没事了  没事了  我来了
Ruth, it's okay. It's okay. I got you.
-把它们弄开  -没事的  好吗  没事了
- Get them off! - You're going to be okay, all right? It's okay.
让开  让开  让开
Move, move, move!
没事了  没事了  没事了  露丝
You're okay. You're okay, you're okay, Ruthie.
快来人啊  快去叫人来
Help! Somebody, get help, now!
没事了  露丝  没事了
You're okay, Ruthie, you're okay.
-都结束了  -把它们弄开  把它们弄开
- It's all finished. - Get them off, get them off.
都没了  露丝  都没了
They're all gone, Ruthie. They're all gone.
把它们弄开  把它们弄开
Get them off me. Get them off. Get them off me.
-把它们弄开  -露丝  都没了
- Get them off me! - Ruthie, they're all gone,
都没了  都没了  好吗
they're all gone, they're all gone, okay?
-把它们弄开  -没事了
- Get them off me. - You're okay.
把它们弄开
Get them off me.
造纸谷镇区
真是千钧一发  希望她没事
It's intense. I hope she's okay.
我看见她了  莎拉刚才也在
I saw her. Sarah was there.
这一切都是她控制的
She was controlling the entire thing.
我姐姐被干掉了
My sister's gone.
接下来就是我们了
We're next.
你找到了吗
You find it?
露易丝·巴普蒂斯特
Louise Baptiste...
露露吗
Lou Lou?
戈德夏尔路220号
220 Goldshire Road.
露易丝·巴普蒂斯特
我又做了那个可怕的梦
I had this messed-up dream again.
我被困在一个红房间里
I was trapped in the red room.
有个苍白的胖女人一直在小声嘟囔
And there's that fat, pale lady who keeps whispering,
"这是个邪恶的地方"
"This is an evil place.
"趁还有机会快跑"
"Run away while you still can."
我害怕女巫会用这个来对付我
I'm scared the witch is going to use it against me.
你们好
Hello.
露露·巴普蒂斯特还住在这吗
Does Lou Lou Baptiste live here still?
我不想轰炸任何人
"I don't want to bomb anybody
除非是需要救...
"if it's not necessary to save..."
狡猾的迪克  总统不该叫这个名字
Tricky Dicky. That's no name for a president.
尼克松的外号
妈妈  你有客人
Mama, you got company!
露露  能听见我们说话吗
Lou Lou, can you hear us?
露·巴
下一个可能是你
You may be the next.
你为什么这么说
Why do you say that?
歌是这么唱的  姑娘
Why, that's the song, girl.
♪ 灵车经过时不要笑 ♪
♪ Don't ever laugh as a hearse goes by ♪
♪ 因为你可能是 ♪
♪ For you may be ♪
♪ 下一个死去的人 ♪
♪ The next to die ♪
莎拉很喜欢这首歌
Sarah loved that song.
她的书在我们手上
We have her book.
你找到了她的书吗  拿来
You found her book? Give it here.
这是我给她的
I give her this.
我真的很可怜那个姑娘
I feel so sorry for that girl,
独自一人坐在黑暗之中
sitting down there in the darkness all by herself.
你妈妈有教过她什么吗
Did your mom ever teach her anything?
教她
Teach her?
黑魔法
Black magic?
没有
No.
这世上没有魔法  孩子
There is no magic, child.
只有愤怒
There is only rage.
那她现在怎么还能写故事
Then how is she still writing the stories?
故事可以伤人
Stories hurt.
故事可以治愈
Stories heal.
你知道你干了什么吗
Do you know what you have done?
干了什么
Done what?
你不该拿走这本书
You shouldn't have taken the book.
你惹怒她了
You made her angry.
"蛆虫爬进又爬出"
"The worms crawl in, the worms crawl out..."
她有时候会神志不清
She gets this way sometimes.
我必须问清楚
Look, I need to know.
改天吧  我得让她平静下来
Another time. I need to settle her down.
不  我们必须问清楚  我必须问清楚
No, we need to know. I need to know.
莎拉在医院上吊自杀后
She told the doctors everything she knew at the hospital
她把知道的一切都告诉医生了
where that disturbed girl hung herself.
但我以为...
But I... I thought...
大家都说莎拉是在家里上吊的
Everyone always said Sarah hanged herself in the house.
你又不在场  妈妈在场
You weren't there. Mama was.
医院有病历
The hospitals have records.
莎拉的病历
Records of Sarah.
那我们还在这儿干什么  快走吧
Then what are we still doing here? Let's go.
今天是大选日  各位
It's election day, folks,
请投出自己的一票
so let your voice be heard.
拒绝战争  拒绝越战
Say no to the war! Say no to Vietnam.
拒绝让我们的孩子们去送死
Say no to sending our children to die.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我们需要一位前患者的病历
We need to see the records of a former patient.
我们不能随便给出患者的病历
We don't give out patient records.
这个...
Well, uh,
我是说
I mean,
她一百年前就去世了
she died about 100 years ago.
她自己或者任何人
I'm sure she or anybody else
应该都不会在乎了
probably doesn't care, you know.
你们几个孩子看病历干什么
Why do you kids wanna look at old patient files for?
这是学校作业
For a school assignment
研究...
on, uh...
人类心理学研究
psychological human studies.
没错  研究
Yes, the studies.
我想老医院的病历
I think they put the files
应该都在红房间里
from the old hospital in the red room.
红房间
Red room?
申请需要六周时间
Six weeks processing time.
最多六周
At most.
需要笔吗
Need a pen?
白费功夫
So much for that.
走
Come on!
不
No.
我们不能进红房间
We are not going to the red room!
不  我们要进红房间
No, we are going to the red room.
-我不去  -你得去
- No, I'm not. - Yes.
不  我不要
No. I'm not doing it.
考夫曼医生请接电话
Dr. Kaufmann to telephone, please.
考夫曼医生
Dr. Kaufmann.
我跟你说了我的梦  我不想去
I told you about my dream. I don't want to go.
原来不是红色而是缩写  没事的
So, it isn't actually red. You're fine.
红房间
病历和审计科
缩写就是红房间  好吗
It is called the red room, okay?
谁说一定要是红色了
Who said it had to be red?
我坚决不去
Count me out.
好吧  那留在这里
Okay. Just... stay here.
很快的  不会有事的
Be quick. It'll be fine.
别被抓到了
Just don't get caught.
红房间
病历和审计科
乔治·弗曼
George Foreman.
他会成为73年的世界冠军
He's going to be the world champion in '73.
你知道自己要去哪吗
You know where you're going?
天啊  天啊  天啊
Oh, God. Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God.
说你呢
You there.
你不该来这里
You're not supposed to be here.
站住
Stop!
红房间
The R.E.D. Room.
病历和审计科
莎拉·贝洛斯
入院记录  心理测试
Admittance records, psychological exams,
进食情况
what she ate...
这里  什么都记录了
This is... everything.
她是被自己的家人送来的
She was admitted by her own family.
彭赫斯特医院
精神病院
这上面说她患有
Says here that she was suffering
检查收治精神病患者莎拉·贝洛斯
色素缺乏-白化病
from achromasia-albinism.
因为她与常人有异  他们就把她关在地下室
They put her in her basement because she was different.
看这个  她的主治医师
Here, her supervising doctor was...
是伊弗列姆·贝洛斯
Dr. Ephraim Bellows.
她亲哥哥吗
Her own brother?
是的
Yeah.
天呐  他们各种折磨她
Jesus! They tortured her.
看  电击
Look, electroshock,
隔绝疗法
isolation therapy,
侧脑电热疗法
lateral cerebral diathermia treatment.
这个呢
What about this thing?
这是什么
What is this?
我见过这种东西
I've seen one of these before.
这是留声机圆筒
It's a wax cylinder.
器材柜
唱片出现之前就是用这个录音的
They used them to make recordings before LPs.
你是说我们能听到莎拉说话了
So, does that mean we're going to get to hear Sarah?
他往这边跑了
He went this way.
拉警报
Sound the alarm!
这回你要说实话
You're going to tell the truth now.
明白吗  莎拉
Aren't you, Sarah?
我没有伤害那些孩子
I didn't hurt the children.
我没有
I didn't.
伊弗列姆
Ephraim...
这不是实话  对不对
That isn't the truth, is it?
不是我干的
I didn't do it.
我没有伤害...
I didn't hurt...
说实话  莎拉
Tell the truth, Sarah.
我是你妹妹啊
I'm your sister...
你毒死了那些孩子
You poisoned those children.
不  不是的
No. No.
我想...
I tried...
我想救他们的
I tried to save them.
但谁也不信我
But nobody listened.
我不想伤害他们  但你们不放我出去
I didn't want them hurt, but you wouldn't let me out.
莎拉
Sarah...
说实话
Tell the truth.
她不知道自己干了什么
She doesn't know what she did.
是水
It was the water.
我们谈过这个了  莎拉
We went over this, Sarah.
是水
The water.
水没有问题
There's nothing wrong with the water.
所以你才被送来这里
That's why you're here.
造纸厂
The mill.
是造纸厂排放的水银
It was the mercury from the mill.
你们污染了水...
You poisoned the wa...
不是她干的
She didn't do it.
是她的家人
It was her family.
莎拉
Sarah,
你还有意识吗
are you still here?
我说
I'll tell you.
你想听什么我都说
I'll tell you what you want to hear.
说来听听
And what's that?
查理梦到了一个红房间
Charlie had a dream of a red room...
查理
Charlie?
红房间
The R.E.D. Room.
哪个查理
Charlie who?
查克
Chuck.
在他的梦里
In his dream,
一个女人脸色苍白
a woman with a pale face,
双眼乌黑
black eyes,
头发又黑又长
and long black hair
梦
悄悄溜进了他的房间
slipped silently into his room.
她俯下身低语
She leaned over and whispered,
"这是个邪恶的地方"
"This is an evil place.
"趁还有机会快跑"
"Run away while you still can."
不妙
That's not good.
查克
Chuck!
救命
Help!
救命  谁来救救我
Help! Somebody, help!
Help! Please, somebody, help.
救命  救命
Help. Help!
谁来救救我
Somebody, help!
快啊
Come on!
查克  查克  你在哪
Chuck! Chuck, where are you?
查克
Chuck!
他在哪
Where is he?
他应该就在这里的
He should be right here.
查克  查克
Chuck? Chuck?
查克
Chuck.
那么
So,
你们的朋友呢
where's your little friend?
继续报道68年大选之夜新闻
News coverage of election night '68 continues.
斯黛拉
Stella?
爸
Dad.
你没事吧  你在哪
Are you okay? Where are you?
斯黛拉
Stella?
爸  恐怕我要死了
I'm afraid I'm gonna die, Dad.
亲爱的  别这么说
Sweetie, don't say that.
告诉我怎么回事  告诉我怎么帮你
Tell me what's wrong. Tell me what I can do.
你什么也做不了
Can't do anything about it.
我也什么都做不了
I can't do anything about it.
不不  你得帮帮我  亲爱的
No, no. You gotta help me out here, sweetie.
告诉我你在哪  我马上过去
Tell me where you are. I will get there right away.
不管你遇到了什么事  你要告诉我
I don't care what you're going through, just tell me, please.
如果我消失了
If I go missing...
消失
Missing?
如果你找不到我了
If you can't find me...
去哪找你
Find you where?
斯黛拉
Stella?
你要知道我没有丢下你
I didn't leave you.
我绝不会那样对你
I would never do that to you.
我不懂
I don't understand
你到底在说什么  斯黛拉  丢下我
what you're talking about, Stella, leave me?
你为什么要丢下我
Why would you leave me?
你旁边是不是有别人  你...
Is someone there with you? Do...
听我说  亲爱的
Please just listen to me, sweetie.
那不是你的错  斯黛拉
It's not your fault, Stella.
她离开不是你的错
It's not your fault she left.
所有人都说是因为我
Everyone said it was because of me.
不  拜托  求你听我说
Oh, no, please, please, please listen to me.
她离开不是你的错
It's not your fault she left.
从来都不是因为你  是她自己
It was never, ever about you. It was about her.
我不知道  内心深处  她...
I don't know, somewhere deep down inside, she just...
感觉被困住了  我也不知道  我...
felt trapped or something, I don't know, I...
事情很复杂
It's complicated.
我也希望能给你答案  亲爱的
I wish I had answers for you, sweetie,
但我没办法  我很抱歉
but I just don't and I'm so sorry.
爸  我爱你  我得挂了
I love you, Dad. I gotta go.
-那不是你的错  斯黛拉  求你别挂  -对不起
- It's not your fault, Stella. Please don't hang up, sweetie. - I'm sorry,
对不起  我得挂了
I'm sorry, I gotta go.
我告诉你  那不是你的错...
I'm telling you, it wasn't your...
如何  你爸来接你吗
So? Is your dad going to come pick you up?
斯黛拉  怎么回事
Stella, what's going on?
我需要你立刻回答我的问题
I need answers from you right now.
明白吗
Understand?
理查德·尼克松得票率仍有43%  汉弗莱35%
Richard Nixon is still holding at 43 and Humphrey 35,
不过华莱士有1%的涨幅
but, uh, Wallace has come up one point.
该我打电话了吧
What about my call?
逃避兵役的家伙没有权利
Rules don't apply to draft dodgers.
你以为我不会发现吗
You think I wouldn't find out?
雷蒙·莫拉莱斯
Ramon Morales.
无论如何你都要为你的国家
You're gonna do your duty to this country
尽你的责任
one way or the other.
把你们失踪的朋友的事告诉我  我才能帮你们
I can help you if you tell us about your missing friends.
我们知道的都告诉你了
Told you everything we know.
是啊
Oh, yeah, right.
莎拉·贝洛斯的书
Sarah Bellows' book.
故事自己出现  然后都成真了
The stories write themselves and it all comes alive.
我们找不到任何尸体
We can't find any bodies.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
很难以置信
It's hard to believe.
我们在学校救了露丝
We saved Ruth at school.
我们阻止了她被杀害
I mean, we stopped her from getting killed.
露丝·施泰因贝格
Ruth Steinberg?
你说的是她吗
That's who you're talking about?
你们才没救人
You didn't save anyone.
她要在精神病院度过余生了
She's stuck in the nuthouse for the rest of her life.
走吧  斯黛拉  你可以走了
Get out of here, Stella. You're free to go.
你比这个逃避兵役的家伙强多了
You're so much better than this draft dodger.
拜托  你爸爸会怎么说
Come on, what would your father say?
我不走
I'm not leaving.
既然你不打算去越南
Since you're not going to 'Nam,
也许拘留一晚会让你松口
maybe a night behind bars will loosen those lips of yours.
走吧  霍布斯
Come on, Hobbs.
回家把钱准备好
Go home, dig out that 10 bucks
等尼克松赢了大选你就欠我十块钱了
you're gonna owe me when Nixon wins,
今晚我来关门
and, uh, I'll close up here.
好  晚安
All right, have a good night.
晚安  小情侣
Nighty-night, lovebirds.
我应该告诉你的
I should've told you.
你肯定觉得我是个懦夫  但是
You must think I'm a coward, but...
我绝对不会那么想
I would never think that.
两个月前他们把我哥从越南运回来了
Two months ago they shipped my brother back from Vietnam
他的尸体残骸
in pieces.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
上周我收到征兵通知的时候
Last week when I got my draft notice,
我没办法
I couldn't.
他们只是让你去送死
They just send you there to die.
如果这本书读了我
If the book reads me,
我担心它会讲述什么
I'm afraid what it's going to say.
吃吧  孩子
There you go, boy.
好吃吧
Yeah, that's good, huh?
《叮里个咚咚叮》
"Me Tie Dough-ty Walker"?
叮里个咚咚叮
这些变态故事是谁想出来的
Who came up with all this sick stuff?
是你吗  斯黛拉
Is this you, Stella?
这些故事不是我们写的
We didn't write the stories.
扳机
Trigger?
等等  有新故事了吗
Wait, is there another story?
求你了  你得放我们出去
Please, you have to let us out!
如果有新故事了
Okay, if there's another story,
我们都会有危险
we are all gonna be in danger.
告诉我们发生了什么
Tell us what's happening!
是什么故事
What's the story?
求你了  听我说好吗
Please just listen to me, okay?
我们都会死
We're all going to die.
轮到我了
It's my turn.
故事里发生了什么
Okay, what happens in the story?
告诉我书里写了哪个名字就行
Just tell me which name is in the book.
雷蒙
Ramon.
是个篝火晚会上讲的故事
It's a campfire story.
曾经把我吓得要死
It used to scare me to death.
叮咚人要来了
The Jangly Man is coming.
-他要带我去...  -发生什么了
- He's going to take me... - What's going on?
他会说那句话的  小心听
He's going to say it. Listen.
叮里个咚咚叮
Me tie dough-ty walker!
你在耍我吗
Are you shitting me?
求你了  放我们出去
Please, just let us out, please!
叮里个咚咚叮
Me tie dough-ty walker!
雷蒙
Ramon!
Ramon.
天啊  雷蒙
Oh, my God, Ramon.
天啊  这是什么
Oh, my God, what is that?
救命  救命啊  有人能听到吗
Help. Help, please. Can someone hear me?
钥匙
Keys.
快
Hurry!
懦夫
Coward!
我拿到钥匙了
I got the keys.
快  快  快
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
懦夫
Coward!
快跑  快  快
Run! Go, go, go!
你还在等什么
What are you waiting for?
回她家去
Go to the house.
告诉她真相
Tell her the truth.
那东西会跟着我
That thing will follow me.
但这些故事每次都成真了
But the stories come true every time.
那你最好跑快点
Then you better run fast.
阻止她你就能阻止这一切
Stop her and you'll stop this.
莎拉
Sarah!
你能听到吗
Can you hear me?
该死的  你不能再讲这些故事了
God damn you! You have to stop telling these stories!
我们又没伤害你
We didn't do anything to you!
我们只想帮你  我们知道你是无辜的
We just want to help you! We know you're innocent!
我们知道你没有给那些孩子下毒
We know you didn't poison the kids!
但是求你了  不要再讲这些故事了
But, please, you just have to stop telling the stories!
斯黛拉
Stella!
你在哪
Where are you?
鬼屋
不不不
No, no, no, no.
斯黛拉
Stella.
Stella!
斯黛拉
Hey, Stella!
她又不在自己房间里
She's out of her room again.
孩子们  莎拉出来了
Boys? Sarah's out!
马上把她找出来
Find her now!
莎拉
Sarah!
交给我吧  哈罗德
You leave that to me, Harold.
莎拉
Sarah!
莎拉  你在哪
Sarah, where are you?
莎拉
Sarah!
我听到了
I hear her.
她在这儿
She's here!
她在这里
She's in here!
莎拉
Sarah!
你在哪
Where are you?
露露
Lou Lou.
你看到莎拉了吗
Did you see Sarah?
没有  女士
No, ma'am.
她在撒谎
She's lying.
你不会撒谎吧  露露
You wouldn't lie, Lou Lou?
不会  女士
No, ma'am.
我没看到莎拉
No, I didn't see Sarah.
不要  贝洛斯先生  求你了
No, Mr. Bellows, please, no!
求你了  不要
Please, no!
你躲不过我们的
You can't hide from us.
抓到你了
Got you!
不  不
No! No!
救救我  救救我
Help me! Help me!
-救救我  -斯黛拉
- Help me! - Stella!
救救我
Please! Help me!
-救救我  -她一直在跟大家说水的事
- Please, help me! - She's been telling everyone about the water.
我们该拿她怎么办
What should we do with her?
-谁来救救我  -闭上你的臭嘴
- Somebody, help me, please. - You're going to shut your ugly mouth
不然我们就帮你把嘴封上
or we're going to shut it for you.
救救我
Please, help me!
Help me, please!
回你该待的地方去
Going back where you belong.
救救我
Help me, please.
把嘴闭上  不然你知道会有什么下场
Be quiet or you know what you'll get.
求求你们  我不是莎拉
Please. I'm not Sarah. Please!
求你们放我走
Please let me go. Please...
放我走
Let me go.
求你们别把我关在这里
Please, don't put me in here.
再敢跑出去  我们就送你去精神病院
Try this again and we'll send you to the asylum.
求求你们  等等
Please. Wait! Please?
你应该待在自己的房间里的
You should have stayed in your room.
求求你们
Please. Please. Please.
不是我干的
I didn't do it.
你不配有灯光
You don't deserve the light.
不
No!
我告诉你了  我告诉你了
I'm telling you, I'm telling you,
我不是莎拉
I'm not Sarah.
求你了
Please.
斯黛拉
Stella...
我还有一个故事
I have another story
专为你准备
just for you.
斯黛拉
Stella,
如果你能听到  不管你在哪里
if you can hear me, wherever you are,
告诉她真相
tell her the truth.
不
No.
该讲故事给你听了  莎拉
It's time that you hear a story, Sarah.
你曾经是受害者
You were a victim.
现在你变成了怪物
Now you've turned into a monster.
变成了他们口中的怪物
The one that they said you were.
斯黛拉
Stella.
你夺走了我的朋友
You took my friends.
我最爱的两个人
Two of the people that I love most.
雷蒙
Ramon!
斯黛拉
Stella!
你也要夺走他吗
Are you going to take him, too?
你的家人对你做了什么
What your family did to you,
他们说了什么  那是他们的错
what they said, that's on them.
但是你的所作所为
But what you do,
这是你的错  莎拉
this is on you, Sarah.
都是你的错
It's all on you.
我会讲述你的故事
I'll tell your story.
真实的故事  我会说出真相
The real story, I'll tell the truth.
但是这种愤怒
But the rage,
愤怒必须停止  莎拉
the rage has to stop, Sarah.
用你的血
Use your blood.
莎拉·贝洛斯是无辜的
Sarah Bellows was innocent.
她知道真相
She knew the truth,
并试图阻止他们
and tried to stop them.
她很勇敢
She was brave.
她被自己的家人
She was harmed and destroyed
伤害并毁灭
by her own family.
被他们的贪婪
By their greed,
他们的谎言
and their lies
和他们的罪恶
and their sins.
我会讲述你的故事
I'll tell your story.
你可以放手了
You can let it go.
你可以放手了  莎拉
You can let it go, Sarah.
故事可以伤人
Stories hurt.
故事可以治愈
Stories heal.
只要讲的次数够多
If we repeat them often enough,
它们就会成真
they become real.
它们有这种力量
They have that power.
它们塑造我们
They make us who we are.
斯黛拉
Stella.
你没事我就放心了
I'm just so happy you're okay.
如果说我从莎拉身上学到了什么
And if there's anything I learned from Sarah,
那就是永不放弃
it's to never give up.
我信守承诺  讲述了莎拉的故事
I told Sarah's story exactly as I promised.
我描述那个在黑暗中写故事的
I wrote about the pale, lonely girl
苍白孤独的女孩
who wrote stories in the dark.
恐怖故事背后的真相
以及她是如何被她的家人变成一个怪物的
And how she was turned into a monster by her family.
优胜故事
作者  斯黛拉·尼科尔斯
有些人相信我  但大多数人不相信
Some people believed me. Most didn't.
因为就像莎拉一样
Because, like Sarah,
我曾经也是一个
I was a lonely girl
擅长讲述恐怖故事的孤独的女孩
who knew how to tell a good creepy story.
专车
写信给我
Write me?
每天都写
Every day.
回头见
See you around.
孩子  你叫什么
What's your name, kid?
雷蒙·莫拉莱斯
Ramon Morales.
除美国陆军车辆外禁止停车
故事可以教导我们关怀
Stories can teach us to care.
它们使我们鼓起勇气
They make us brave enough
承认我们需要彼此
to admit that we need each other.
给我们一个可以回去的家
Give us a home to go back to.
请尽快回家
爱你的斯黛拉
查克和奥吉还没回来
Chuck and Auggie are still gone,
但我知道有办法带他们回来
but I know there is a way to bring them back
而秘密就在书中
and that the secret is in the book.
不找到他们
And we won't stop...
我们决不放弃
until we find them.
在黑暗中讲述的恐怖故事